Let's understand Gradient Descent, an algorithm for
finding the minimum of a function.
Imagine you're on a hill, and you want to find the lowest point.
You can do this by taking steps downhill,
in the direction of the steepest descent.
The gradient of a function tells us the direction of
the steepest ascent. So, we move in the opposite direction.
Step 1. We calculate the gradient and take a step downhill.
Step 2. We calculate the gradient and take a step downhill.
Step 3. We calculate the gradient and take a step downhill.
Step 4. We calculate the gradient and take a step downhill.
Step 5. We calculate the gradient and take a step downhill.
We continue this process, taking smaller and
smaller steps as we approach the minimum.
Eventually, we converge to the lowest point of the function.