Imagine a game of chess. After just the first
few moves, things can get really complex, really quickly!
Let's explore the sheer number of possible moves after only 10 moves.
This graph shows approximately how many different
chess games are possible after each move.
After just one move per player, there are already 20 possible games!
That number jumps to 400 after two moves each.
After five moves, it's already hard
to imagine: almost 200,000 possible games!
But after 10 moves, things explode.
Over 3 billion different possible chess
games exist after just 10 moves!
That's why chess is so amazing. It's a game of
near infinite possibilities, even in just a few moves.