This is a circle with radius 1, so the length of
the circumference is tau. The method we're using here to approximate
tau is to inscribe and circumscribe two polygons around the circle,
and the lengths of the polygons' perimeters will approach the length
of the circumference as we increase the number of sides. This
method is known as the method of exhaustion or Archimedes' method.
Let's first draw an inscribed hexagon. The circumradius is 1, so
the side length is also 1. We use the notation I
6 to represent the side length of the inscribed hexagon.
Let's generalize this length and call it I N, where N is the number
of sides. Let's draw a line from the center of the circle to one
of the endpoints. It is also a radius, so its length is 1.
This length is half of the polygon's side,
so its length is I N over 2.
Using the Pythagorean theorem, we can find
the length of the polygon's apothem.
This length together with the apothem forms a radius, so
its length is 1 minus the length of the apothem.
Using the Pythagorean theorem, we can calculate this length, and by simplifying
it, we find this length to be the square root of 2
minus the square root of 4 minus I N squared.
This line is also a side of an inscribed 2 N
gon, so it can be written as I 2 N.
This is a circumscribed hexagon, its apothem is
also a radius, so its length is 1.
Using the ratio of a 30 60 90 triangle's sides, we can
find the side length of this hexagon to be 2 times the
square root of 3 all over 3. We use the notation C
6 to represent the side length of the circumscribed hexagon.
Let's generalize this hexagon to be a circumscribed N gon and draw a circumscribed
2 N gon, where its side length is C 2 N by definition.
This line is a side of the inscribed N gon, so its length is I N.
This line is a side of the circumscribed 2 N gon, so
if we halve it we get C 2 N over 2.
This line is a side of the circumscribed N gon, so
if we halve it we get C N over 2.
This triangle and this triangle are both isosceles and share
the same angle at their apexes, so they are similar,
and their relation can be expressed as two equal ratios.
After simplifying the equation, we get the formula for finding C 2 N.
Because the inscribed polygon's perimeter is less than the
circumference is less than the circumscribed polygon's perimeter, we
can express this relation by this inequality.
Let's try using this method to approximate tau to the second
digit after decimal. The perimeters of the polygons match up to
two decimal places when we reach N equals 96. We can
thus conclude that tau must be approximately equal to 6.28.