Imagine you're standing on this curve, and
you want to find the lowest point.
You can't see the whole curve, so you need a way
to find the minimum just by feeling the slope around you.
That's where Gradient Descent comes in. It's like
taking small steps downhill, following the steepest descent.
We calculate the slope at our current location and
take a step downhill. The size of the step
is controlled by a parameter called the learning rate.
We calculate the slope at our current location and
take a step downhill. The size of the step
is controlled by a parameter called the learning rate.
We calculate the slope at our current location and
take a step downhill. The size of the step
is controlled by a parameter called the learning rate.
We calculate the slope at our current location and
take a step downhill. The size of the step
is controlled by a parameter called the learning rate.
We calculate the slope at our current location and
take a step downhill. The size of the step
is controlled by a parameter called the learning rate.
By repeatedly taking these steps, we get closer and
closer to the minimum point of the function.
And that's Gradient Descent in a nutshell! A
simple yet powerful algorithm for finding minimums.